<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Coriumancer</name>
		<description>The Artificer Coriumancer from the D&amp;D Wiki.</description>
		<author url="https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Coriumancer_(5e_Subclass)">Durkmenistan</author>
		<update version="1.0.0">
			<file name="Coriumancer.xml" url="https://github.com/adurkee93/D-D-Homebrew/blob/main/Coriumancer.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Artificer (HB)" type="Class" source="Homebrew" id="ID_WIKI_UA20190228_CLASS_ARTIFICER">
		<description>
			<p>Masters of unlocking magic in everyday objects, artificers are supreme inventors. They see magic as a complex system waiting to be decoded and controlled. Artificers use tools to channel arcane power, crafting temporary and permanent magical objects. To cast a spell, an artificer could use alchemist’s supplies to create a potent elixir, calligrapher’s supplies to inscribe a sigil of power on an ally’s armor, or tinker’s tools to craft a temporary charm. The magic of artificers is tied to their tools and their talents.</p>
			<h4>ARCANE SCIENCE</h4>
			<p>In the world of Eberron, arcane magic has been harnessed as a form of science and deployed throughout society. Artificers reflect this development. Their knowledge of magical devices, and their ability to infuse mundane items with magical energy, allows the grand magical projects of Eberron to continue running.</p>
			<p class="indent">During the Last War, artificers were marshaled on a massive scale. Many lives were saved because of the inventions of brave artificers, but also countless lives were lost because of the mass destruction that artificers’ creations unleashed.</p>
			<h4>SEEKERS OF NEW LORE</h4>
			<p>Nothing excites an artificer quite like uncovering a new metal or discovering a source of elemental energy. In artificer circles, new inventions and strange discoveries create the most excitement. Artificers who wish to make a mark must find something fresh, rather than uncover someone else’s work.</p>
			<p class="indent">This drive for novelty pushes artificers to become adventurers. Eberron’s main travel routes and populated regions have long since been explored. Thus, artificers take to the edge of civilization in hopes of making the next great discovery in arcane research.</p>
			<h4>CREATING AN ARTIFICER</h4>
			<p>When creating an artificer character, think about your character’s background and drive for adventure. Does the character have a rival? What is the character’s relationship with the artisan or artificer who taught the basics of the craft? Talk to your DM about the role played by artificers in the campaign, and what sort of organizations and NPCs you might have ties to.</p>
			<h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>You can make an artificer quickly by following these suggestions. First, put your highest ability score in Intelligence, followed by Constitution or Dexterity. Second, choose the guild artisan background.</p>
			<h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
			<p>As an artificer, you gain the following class features.</p>
			<h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per artificer level</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per artificer level after 1st</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, medium armor, shields</li>
				<li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, hand crossbows, heavy crossbows</li>
				<li><strong>Tools:</strong> Thieves’ tools, tinker’s tools, one type of artisan’s tools of your choice</li>
			</ul>
			<p></p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Intelligence</li>
				<li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Arcana, History, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Sleight of Hand</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
			<p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>any two simple weapons</li>
				<li>a light crossbow and 20 bolts</li>
				<li>(<i>a</i>) studded leather armor or (<i>b</i>) scale mail</li>
				<li>thieves’ tools and a dungeoneer’s pack</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">If you forgo this starting equipment, as well as the items offered by your background, you start with 5d4 × 10 gp to buy your equipment.</p>
			<div class="sidebar">
				<h5>OPTIONAL RULE: FIREARM PROFICIENCY</h5>
				<p>The creation and operation of gunpowder weapons have been discovered in various corners of the D&amp;D multiverse. If your Dungeon Master uses the rules on firearms in the Dungeon Master’s Guide (p. 267) and your artificer has been exposed to the operation of such weapons, your artificer is proficient with them.</p>
			</div>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGICAL_TINKERING" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SPELLCASTING" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_INFUSE_ITEM" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ARTIFICER_SPECIALIST" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_TOOL_EXPERTISE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ARCANE_ARMAMENT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_THE_RIGHT_CANTRIP_FOR_THE_JOB" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SPELL_STORING_ITEM" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SOUL_OF_ARTIFICE" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="hd">d8</set>
			<set name="short">Masters of unlocking magic in everyday objects, artificers are supreme inventors.</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_HALF" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>

			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20190228_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HAND" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20190228_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HEAVY" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20190228_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_TINKERS_TOOLS" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Artisan’s Tool, Artificer" supports="Artisan tools" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20190228_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20190228_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20190228_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Artificer" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20190228_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />

			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGICAL_TINKERING" level="1" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SPELLCASTING" level="1" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_INFUSE_ITEM" level="2" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ARTIFICER_SPECIALIST" level="3" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_TOOL_EXPERTISE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ARCANE_ARMAMENT" level="5" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_THE_RIGHT_CANTRIP_FOR_THE_JOB" level="10" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SPELL_STORING_ITEM" level="18" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SOUL_OF_ARTIFICE" level="20" />
		</rules>
		<multiclass id="ID_WOTC_UA20190228_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER">
			<prerequisite>Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[int:13], !(ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_ARTIFICER||ID_WOTC_UA_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER||ID_WOTC_ERLW_CLASS_ARTIFICER||ID_WOTC_ERLW_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER)</requirements>
			<setters>
				<set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, shields, thieves’ tools, tinker’s tools.</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
			</rules>
		</multiclass>
	</element>
	<element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SPELLCASTING">
		<description>
			<p>You have studied the workings of magic, how to channel it through objects, and how to awaken it within them. As a result, you have gained a limited ability to cast spells. To observers, you don’t appear to be casting spells in a conventional way; you look as if you’re producing wonders through various items.</p>
			<h5>TOOLS REQUIRED</h5>
			<p>You produce your artificer spell effects through your tools. You must have a spellcasting focus—specifically thieves’ tools or some kind of artisan’s tool—in hand when you cast any spell with this Spellcasting feature. You must be proficient with the tool to use it in this way. See chapter 5, “Equipment,” in the Player’s Handbook for descriptions of these tools.</p>
			<p class="indent">After you gain the Infuse Item feature at 2nd level, you can also use any item bearing one of your infusions as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			<h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
			<p>At 1st level, you know two cantrips of your choice from the artificer spell list below. At higher levels, you learn additional artificer cantrips of your choice, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Artificer table.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the artificer cantrips you know with another cantrip from the artificer spell list.</p>
			<h5>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</h5>			
			<p>The Artificer table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your artificer spells. To cast one of your artificer spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">You prepare the list of artificer spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the artificer spell list. When you do so, choose a number of artificer spells equal to your Intelligence modifier + half your artificer level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
			<p class="indent">For example, if you are a 5th-level artificer, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With an Intelligence of 14, your list of prepared spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of artificer spells requires time spent in tinkering with your spellcasting focuses: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</p>
			<h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
			<p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your artificer spells; your understanding of the theory behind magic allows you to wield these spells with superior skill. You use your Intelligence whenever an artificer spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for an artificer spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
			<center>
				<p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
				<p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
			</center>
			<h5>RITUAL CASTING</h5>
			<p>You can cast an artificer spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.</p>
			<div class="sidebar">
				<h5>THE MAGIC OF ARTIFICE</h5>
				<p>As an artificer, you use tools when you cast your spells. When describing your spellcasting, think about how you’re using a tool to perform the spell effect. If you cast cure wounds using alchemist’s supplies, you could be quickly producing a salve. If you cast it using tinker’s tools, you might have a miniature mechanical spider that binds wounds. When you cast poison spray, you could fling foul chemicals or use a wand that spits venom. The effect of the spell is the same as for a spellcaster of any other class, but your method of spellcasting is special.</p>
				<p class="indent">The same principle applies when you prepare your spells. As an artificer, you don’t study a spellbook or pray to prepare your spells. Instead, you work with your tools and create the specialized items you’ll use to produce your effects. If you replace cure wounds with shocking grasp, you might be breaking down the device you used to heal and creating an offensive item in its place—perhaps a gauntlet that lets you channel a surge of energy.</p>
				<p class="indent">Such details don’t limit you in any way or provide you with any benefit. You don’t have to justify how you’re using tools to cast a spell. But describing your spellcasting creatively is a fun way to distinguish yourself from other spellcasters.</p>
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You produce your artificer spell effects through your tools. You must have a spellcasting focus—specifically thieves’ tools or some kind of artisan’s tool—in hand when you cast any spell with this Spellcasting feature. You must be proficient with the tool to use it in this way.</description>
		</sheet>
		<spellcasting name="Artificer" ability="Intelligence" prepare="true">
			<list known="true">Homebrew Artificer</list>
		</spellcasting>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />

			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="1" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="5" />

			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="5" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="7" />

			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="9" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="11" />

			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="15" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="17" />

			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="19" />

			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:prepare" value="intelligence:modifier" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:artificer:half" />

			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Artificer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="1" number="2" spellcasting="Artificer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Artificer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="10" number="1" spellcasting="Artificer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Artificer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="14" number="1" spellcasting="Artificer" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Artificer Specialist" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ARTIFICER_SPECIALIST">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you choose the type of specialist you are: Alchemist or Artillerist, each of which is detailed at the end of the class’s description. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th and 14th level.</p>
			<div class="sidebar">
				<h5>VARIANT: CRAFTING</h5>
				<p>An artificer subclass makes you more efficient at crafting certain items. The feature you get from your subclass works whether you’re using the crafting rules in the Player’s Handbook, Dungeon Master’s Guide, or Xanathar’s Guide to Everything.</p>
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype" name="Artificer Specialist" supports="Homebrew Artificer Specialist" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ACID_SPLASH">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_BOLT">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDANCE">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MESSAGE">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POISON_SPRAY">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_FROST">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RESISTANCE">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHOCKING_GRASP">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPARE_THE_DYING">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THORN_WHIP">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CREATE_BONFIRE">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FROSTBITE">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAGIC_STONE">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_THUNDERCLAP">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer</supports>
	</append>
	
	<element name="Coriumancer" type="Archetype" source="Homebrew" id="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_CORIUMANCER">
		<supports>Homebrew Artificer Specialist</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When the battle’s over, the average party leaves the most valuable loot behind. The Coriumancer recognizes the innate power of flesh, and utilizes their skill to empower their party with the abilities of their defeated foes. The Coriumancer’s expertise allows them to moonlight as a healer as well. </p>
			<div element="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_TOOLS_OF_THE_TRADE" />
			<div element="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_FLESH_FETISH" />
			<div element="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_BODYSNATCHER" />
			<div element="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_TAXIDERMIST" />
			<div element="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_TROPHY_HUNTER" />
			<div element="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_CORPSE_EATER" />
			<div element="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_SPELLSTORE" />
			<div element="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_LEND_A_HAND" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">The Coriumancer focuses on casting buffs using catalysts created from corpses of defeated foes.</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>The Coriumancer focuses on casting buffs using catalysts created from corpses of defeated foes.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_TOOLS_OF_THE_TRADE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" name="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_FLESH_FETISH" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" name="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_BODYSNATCHER" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" name="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_TAXIDERMIST" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" name="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_TROPHY_HUNTER" level="9" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" name="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_CORPSE_EATER" level="15" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" name="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_SPELLSTORE" level="18" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" name="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_LEND_A_HAND" level="18" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS" level="3" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE" level="3" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID" level="5" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE" level="5" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_HEALING_WORD" level="9" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY" level="9" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" level="13" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGE_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE" level="13" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION" level="17" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS" level="17" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Surgeon's Tools" type="Item" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_ITEM_TOOL_SURGEONS_TOOLS">
		<description>
			<p>Surgeon's tools enable a character to perform surgery or dissections, including taking specimens for later research.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Components.</em></strong> Surgeon's tools come in a wooden box, and include forceps, two scalpels, a retractor, surgical scissors, a needle with limited sinew for sewing, a bonesaw, a vial of antiseptic and clean linen for bandages.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Arcana.</em></strong> Proficiency with surgeon's tools allows you to unlock more information on Intelligence checks involving wounds and dissection.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Investigation.</em></strong>When you inspect an area for clues, proficiency with surgeon's tools grants additional insight into any blood stains in the area. When you inspect a creature, it grants additional insight into the circumstances of its wounds.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Tools</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">50</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="8">8 lbs.</set>
			<set name="type">Tool</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SURGEONS_TOOLS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!--element name="Tool Proficiency (Surgeon's Tools)" type="Archetype Feature" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SURGEONS_TOOLS">
		<supports>Tool Proficiency</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Surgeon's tools enable a character to perform surgery or dissections, including taking specimens for later research.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Proficiency with surgeon's tools</description>
		</sheet>
	</element-->
	
	<element name="Tool Proficiency (Surgeon's Tools)" type="Proficiency" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SURGEONS_TOOLS">
		<description>
			<p>These special tools include the items needed to pursue a craft or trade. Proficiency with a set of artisan’s tools lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make using the tools in your craft.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Tools of the Trade" type="Archetype Feature" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_TOOLS_OF_THE_TRADE">
		<description>
			<p>By the time you adopt this specialty at 3rd level, you’re deeply familiar with employing its tools.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Proficiencies.</em></strong>  You gain proficiency with surgeon's tools and herbalism kit, assuming you don’t already have them. You also gain surgeon's tools and an herbalism kit for free—the result of tinkering you’ve done as you’ve prepared for this specialization.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You gain proficiency with surgeon's tools and herbalism kit, assuming you don’t already have them. You also gain surgeon's tools and an herbalism kit for free—the result of tinkering you’ve done as you’ve prepared for this specialization.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SURGEONS_TOOLS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Flesh Fetish" type="Archetype Feature" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_FLESH_FETISH">
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 3rd level, your focus in the art of coriumancy has resulted in the devolution of your skills in other areas. Besides the innate prepared spells of the subclass, you can no longer prepare Artificer spells normally. Instead, you may prepare only spells for which you have a coriumancy catalyst in your possession.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You cannot prepare Artificer spells normally. Instead, you may prepare only spells for which you have a coriumancy catalyst in your possession.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Bodysnatcher" type="Archetype Feature" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_BODYSNATCHER">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 3rd level, you acquire the ability to create a basic coriumancy catalyst, a non-magical item derived from a fresh corpse or living body. You must have appropriate tools and proficiency to harvest the specimen. The creature of origin must be of the same or lower level as you, and the catalyst must be properly extracted from the creature. Basic catalysts have a decay rate, with items made from flesh and blood becoming invalid faster than those of horn or carapace. You may analyze an existing specimen you encounter, to determine whether it may function as a basic catalyst.</p>
			<p>Starting at 3rd level, you may prepare any spells during a long rest for which you have a basic catalyst in your possession. When a spell associated with a basic catalyst is cast, one specimen of that catalyst in the caster’s possession is permanently consumed.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have the ability to create a basic coriumancy catalyst, a non-magical item derived from a fresh corpse or living body. You must have appropriate tools and proficiency to harvest the specimen. The creature of origin must be of the same or lower level as you, and the catalyst must be properly extracted from the creature. Basic catalysts have a decay rate, with items made from flesh and blood becoming invalid faster than those of horn or carapace. You may analyze an existing specimen you encounter, to determine whether it may function as a basic catalyst.</description>
			<description>Starting at 3rd level, you may prepare any spells during a long rest for which you have a basic catalyst in your possession. When a spell associated with a basic catalyst is cast, one specimen of that catalyst in the caster’s possession is permanently consumed.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Taxidermist" type="Archetype Feature" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_TAXIDERMIST">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 5th level, you acquire the ability to create a preserved coriumancy catalyst, a magical item made from a basic coriumancy catalyst that has not yet decayed. You must have appropriate tools and proficiency to preserve the basic catalyst, but the method can vary, and may include crystallization, drying, embalming, encasement in glass, petrification, plastination, smoking, tanning, etc. Improper storage of a preserved catalyst, such as embalming a hand and keeping it in your backpack without protecting it from bludgeoning damage, may result in its dysfunction. You may analyze an existing trinket or other item you encounter, to determine whether it may function as a preserved catalyst.</p>
			<p>Starting at 5th level, during a long rest, you may prepare any spells for which you have an attuned preserved catalyst in your possession as cantrips instead of spells. When a cantrip or spell associated with a preserved catalyst is cast, nothing is consumed (besides a spell slot, if applicable).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have the ability to create a preserved coriumancy catalyst, a magical item made from a basic coriumancy catalyst that has not yet decayed. You must have appropriate tools and proficiency to preserve the basic catalyst, but the method can vary, and may include crystallization, drying, embalming, encasement in glass, petrification, plastination, smoking, tanning, etc. Improper storage of a preserved catalyst, such as embalming a hand and keeping it in your backpack without protecting it from bludgeoning damage, may result in its dysfunction. You may analyze an existing trinket or other item you encounter, to determine whether it may function as a preserved catalyst.</description>
			<description>Starting at 5th level, during a long rest, you may prepare any spells for which you have an attuned preserved catalyst in your possession as cantrips instead of spells. When a cantrip or spell associated with a preserved catalyst is cast, nothing is consumed (besides a spell slot, if applicable).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Trophy Hunter" type="Archetype Feature" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_TROPHY_HUNTER">
		<description>
			<p>At 9th level, you may fashion a basic catalyst from any creature killed by your party, regardless of level. The targets of your catalyst-based casts no longer need to be willing. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have the ability to fashion a basic catalyst from any creature killed by your party, regardless of level. The targets of your catalyst-based casts no longer need to be willing. </description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Spell-Storing Item" type="Class Feature" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_SPELLSTORE">
		<description>
			<p>At 18th level, you do not gain the ability to store spells with objects like other Artificers, since to an extent Coriumancers already do this. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You cannot store spells in objects. Instead, whenever you finish a long rest, you can touch one preserved catalyst and make its spell accessible to other creatures at 2nd-level. While holding the modified catalyst, a creature can take an action to produce the spell's effect from it using your spellcasting ability modifier. The spell stays in the object until it has been used a number of times equal to twice your Intelligence modifier (minimum of twice) or until you use this feature again to store a spell in an object. </description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Lend a Hand" type="Archetype Feature" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_LEND_A_HAND">
		<description>
			<p>Instead of spell-storing, whenever you finish a long rest, you can touch one preserved catalyst and make its spell accessible to other creatures at 2nd-level. While holding the modified catalyst, a creature can take an action to produce the spell's effect from it using your spellcasting ability modifier. The spell stays in the object until it has been used a number of times equal to twice your Intelligence modifier (minimum of twice) or until you use this feature again to store a spell in an object. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You cannot store spells in objects. Instead, whenever you finish a long rest, you can touch one preserved catalyst and make its spell accessible to other creatures at 2nd-level. While holding the modified catalyst, a creature can take an action to produce the spell's effect from it using your spellcasting ability modifier. The spell stays in the object until it has been used a number of times equal to twice your Intelligence modifier (minimum of twice) or until you use this feature again to store a spell in an object. </description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Corpse Eater" type="Archetype Feature" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORIUMANCER_CORPSE_EATER">
		<description>
			<p>At 15th level, you may use a fresh corpse that you are touching as a catalyst, and cast a single spell of a spell level of your choice which grants every status harvestable from the corpse. The spell may target as many creatures within range as you like, but no catalysts may be made from the corpse afterward.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You may use a fresh corpse that you are touching as a catalyst, and cast a single spell of a spell level of your choice which grants every status harvestable from the corpse. The spell may target as many creatures within range as you like, but no catalysts may be made from the corpse afterward.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

</elements>
